Reading
The Road to Modern English
At the end of the 16th century, about five to seven million people spoke English.
Nearly all of them lived in England.
Later in the next century,
people from England made voyages to conquer other parts of the world
and because of that, English began to be spoken in many other countries.
Today, more people speak English as their first,
second or a foreign language than ever before.
Native English speakers can understand each other even if they don’t speak the same kind of English.
I’d like to come up to your apartment.
So why has English changed over time?
Actually all languages change and develop when cultures meet
and communicate with each other.
At first the English spoken in England between about AD 450
and 1150 was very different from the English spoken today.
It was based more on German than the English we speak at present.
Then gradually between about AD 800 and 1150,
English became less like German because those who ruled England spoke first Danish
and later French.
These new settlers enriched the English language and especially its vocabulary.
In 1620 some British settlers moved to America.
English began to be spoken in both countries.
At that time two big changes in English spelling happened:
First, Samuel Johnson wrote his dictionary,
and later Noah Webster wrote the American
Dictionary of the English Language.
The latter gave a separate identity to American English spelling.
English now is also spoken as a foreign or second language in South Asia.
For example, India has a very large number of fluent English speakers
because Britain ruled India from 1765 to 1947.
During that time English became the language for government
and education.
Today the number of people learning English in China is increasing rapidly.
In fact, China may have the largest number of English learners.
Will Chinese English develop its own identity?
Only time will tell.